Guide to the J. Walter Thompson Company. James Kennedy papers, 1979-1983 and undated RL.11591
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
J. Walter Thompson Company. James Kennedy papers
1979-1983 and undated
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
J. Walter Thompson Company
John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History
RL.11591
12.0 Linear Feet
Founded in 1864, the J. Walter Thompson Company (JWT) is one of the oldest and largest enduring advertising agencies in the United States. It is headquartered in New York. Kennedy was an executive and Director of Human Resources. Collection includes correspondence, brochures, research reports and other printed materials. JWT subsidiaries and other firms represented include Brouillard Communications, Hill & Knowlton, Lansdowne, Lord Geller Federico & Einstein, Soskin/Thompson Associates and Thompson Recruitment Advertising. Materials touch on a variety of topics relating to personnel management, including affirmative action, alcohol counseling, career development, compensation, executive succession, professional development, retirement and training. Acquired as part of the John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History.
Arrangement
Organized into the following series: Correspondence; Subject Files.
Biographical / Historical
Founded in 1864, the J. Walter Thompson Company (JWT) is one of the oldest and largest enduring advertising agencies in the United States. It is headquartered in New York. Kennedy was an executive and Director of Human Resources.
BA, Stanford University, 1959; Account Management, Foote Cone Belding, 1960; Personnel, General Foods, 1966; joined JWT 1979, Director of Human Resources 1980
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Provenance
The J. Walter Thompson Company. James Kennedy papers were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a gift in 1987.
Related Materials
Related materials may be found in the following Hartman Center collections:
Arthur Einstein papers
Gene Federico papers
J. Walter Thompson Company. Alun Jones papers
J. Walter Thompson Company. Don Robertson papers
J. Walter Thompson Company. Herbert Eames papers
J. Walter Thompson Company. Jack Peters papers
J. Walter Thompson Company. Jack Stevens papers
J. Walter Thompson Company. Joseph O'Donnell papers
J. Walter Thompson Company. Peter A. Schweitzer papers
Thomas F. Garbett papers
Collection Overview
Collection includes correspondence, brochures, research reports and other printed materials. JWT subsidiaries and other firms represented include Brouillard Communications, Hill & Knowlton, Lansdowne, Lord Geller Federico & Einstein, Soskin/Thompson Associates and Thompson Recruitment Advertising. Materials touch on a variety of topics relating to personnel management, including affirmative action, alcohol counseling, career development, compensation, executive succession, professional development, retirement and training. Acquired as part of the John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History.
Advertising; Advertising agencies; Advertising executives; Affirmative action programs -- United States -- Management; Alcoholism -- Treatment; Career education; Retirement -- United States -- Planning; Employees -- Training of; John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History; Brouillard Communications, Inc.; Hill & Knowlton, Inc.; Lord, Geller, Federico, Einstein; Thompson Recruitment Advertising
- Correspondence and Memoranda, 1979-1982; 1
  - Individuals and Institutions, 1979-1982; 1
    - AAAA, 1981-1982; 2 folders (Box 1)
    - AAAA--Loaned Executive Assignment Program (LEAP), 1979-1981 (Box 1)
    - Alan Katcher (consultant), 1981 (Box 1)
    - Alan Middleton, 1982 (Box 1)
    - Alida Blanco, 1981 (Box 1)
    - Barry Stobbs, 1981 (Box 1)
    - Bill Campbell, 1980-1981 (Box 1)
    - Bill Seifert, 1982 (Box 1)
    - Bill Thompson, 1982 (Box 1)
    - Bob Nelson, 1981 (Box 1)
    - Brouillard Communications, 1981 (Box 1)
    - Burkhard Schwarz (Frankfurt), 1981 (Box 1)
    - Burt Manning, 1980-1981 (Box 1)
    - Cardio-Fitness Center, 1980-1982 (Box 1)
    - Colin Dawkins, 1981 (Box 1)
    - Communispond, 1980 (Box 1)
    - Connie (Constance) Ivie, 1979-1981 (Box 1)
    - Dan Kelly (Tokyo), 1981 (Box 1)
    - David Johnston (Singapore), 1981 (Box 1)
    - Denis Lanigan, 1980-1982; 2 folders (Box 1)
    - Dick Pell, 1980 (Box 1)
    - Don Deaton (Hill & Knowlton), 1980-1982 (Box 1)
    - Don Gilbert (consultant), 1979-1980 (Box 1)
    - Don Johnston, 1979-1982 (Box 2)
    - Don Robertson, 1981-1982 (Box 2)
    - Don Thompson, 1981-1982 (Box 2)
    - Drake Beam Morin, 1982 (Box 2)
    - Ed Lanzo, 1981 (Box 2)
    - Ed McCallin, 1980-1981 (Box 2)
    - Edward Keating, 1981 (Box 2)
    - Eli Acimen, 1982 (Box 2)
    - Euro-Dusseldorf, 1981-1982; 2 folders (Box 2)
    - Gemini Group, 1981 (Box 2)
    - Gen. A.P. (Pat) McMillan, 1980-1982 (Box 2)
    - Greg Bathon, 1980-1981 (Box 2)
    - Harry Clark, 1979 (Box 2)
    - Herbert Eames, 1980-1982 (Box 2)
    - Hill & Knowlton, 1981 (Box 2)
    - HomEquity (relocation housing service), 1981-1982 (Box 2)
    - InSci (data management service), 1981 (Box 2)
    - Jack Cronin, 1982 (Box 2)
    - Jackie Treacy, 1980-1982 (Box 2)
    - James Goble, 1982 (Box 2)
    - James Kennedy, 1979 (Box 2)
    - Jeffrey von der Schulenberg (Frankfurt), 1980-1982 (Box 2)
    - Jim Ahtes, 1982 (Box 2)
    - Jim Allman, 1982 (Box 2)
    - Jim Willette (Thompson Recruitment), 1981 (Box 2)
    - Joe McMahon (consultant), 1979-1981 (Box 2)
    - John Sharman (Sydney), 1982 (Box 2)
    - John Willie, 1982 (Box 2)
    - Kent Black, 1981-1982 (Box 2)
    - Korn/Ferry, 1980 (Box 2)
    - Lansdowne, 1980-1982 (Box 2)
    - Leanna Cannonero, 1981 (Box 2)
    - Lee Preschel, 1982 (Box 2)
    - Lord Geller Federico & Einstein, 1980-1982 (Box 2)
    - Malcolm Glenn (Hong Kong), 1982 (Box 2)
    - Max Gosling, 1982 (Box 2)
    - Michael Kennedy, 1981 (Box 3)
    - Nelson Rosabel, 1981 (Box 3)
    - Peter Dunham (consultant), 1981 (Box 3)
    - Peter Rogen, 1981 (Box 3)
    - Pierre LeDuc, 1982 (Box 3)
    - Price Waterhouse, 1980 (Box 3)
    - Ram Ray (Calcutta), 1981 (Box 3)
    - Robert Popper, 1981-1982 (Box 3)
    - Robert Wilson, 1982 (Box 3)
    - Roberta (Bobbie) Howison, 1979-1982 (Box 3)
    - Robin Restall, 1980 (Box 3)
    - Ron Burns, 1982 (Box 3)
    - Ron Kovas (Toronto), 1980 (Box 3)
    - Ross Howarth (Sydney), 1982 (Box 3)
    - Russ Reynolds Associates (CFO search), 1980 (Box 3)
    - Ruth Weir, 1980-1982 (Box 3)
    - Sam Meek III, 1982 (Box 3)
    - Sanford Kornberg, 1982 (Box 3)
    - Selig Danzig (consultant), 1980 (Box 3)
    - Shingo Ino (Tokyo), 1982 (Box 3)
    - Soskin/Thompson Associates, 1980-1982 (Box 3)
    - Terry Coveny, 1980-1981 (Box 3)
    - Thompson Recruitment Advertising, 1980 (Box 3)
    - Tom Sutton, 1982 (Box 3)
    - Vincent Negre, 1981-1982 (Box 3)
    - Wally O'Brien, 1982 (Box 3)
    - Walter F. Meads (consultant), 1979-1982 (Box 3)
    - Wayne Fickinger, 1979-1981 (Box 3)
  - JWT Offices, 1979-1982; 2
    - Interoffice correspondence, 1980 (Box 3)
    - Amsterdam, 1982 (Box 3)
    - Athens, 1980 (Box 3)
    - Atlanta, 1979-1980; 2 folders (Box 3)
    - Australia, 1980-1982 (Box 4)
    - Barcelona, 1980-1981 (Box 4)
    - Bogota, 1982 (Box 4)
    - Brazil, 1981 (Box 4)
    - Buenos Aires, 1980-1982; 2 folders (Box 4)
    - Canada, 1980 (Box 4)
    - Caracas, 1980-1982; 2 folders (Box 4)
    - Chicago, 1979-1982; 3 folders (Box 4)
    - Dallas, 1979 (Box 4)
    - Detroit, 1979-1981; 2 folders (Box 4)
    - Hong Kong, 1981-1982; 2 folders (Box 5)
    - Japan, 1981-1982 (Box 5)
    - Johannesburg, 1981-1982 (Box 5)
    - Kuala Lumpur, 1981-1982; 2 folders (Box 5)
    - London, 1979-1982; 2 folders (Box 5)
    - Los Angeles, 1980-1982; 3 folders (Box 5)
    - Madrid, 1980-1982 (Box 5)
    - Manila, 1981-1982; 2 folders (Box 5)
    - Mexico City, 1980-1982; 2 folders (Box 6)
    - Miami, 1979; 2 folders (Box 6)
    - Milan, 1981-1982 (Box 6)
    - Montreal, 1980-1982; 2 folders (Box 6)
    - New York (includes office move to 466 Lexington), 1979-1982; 4 folders (Box 6)
    - Paris, 1981 (Box 6)
    - Pittsburgh, 1981 (Box 6)
    - San Francisco, 1979-1982; 2 folders (Box 6)
    - Santiago, 1981 (Box 6)
    - Singapore, 1979-1982; 2 folders (Box 6)
    - Switzerland, 1982 (Box 6)
    - Sydney, 1981-1982 (Box 6)
    - Tokyo, 1980-1982; 2 folders (Box 6)
    - Toronto, 1979-1982; 2 folders (Box 7)
    - U.S. Western Division, 1981 (Box 7)
    - Vancouver, 1979-1980; 2 folders (Box 7)
    - Washington (D.C.), 1979-1981 (Box 7)
- Subject Files, 1979-1983 and undated; 2
  - 3 Year Marketing Plans binder, 1982 (Box 8)
  - Administrative users (data processing), 1981 (Box 8)
  - Alcohol counseling program, 1980 (Box 8)
  - Asia-Pacific Management Meeting, 1982 (Box 8)
  - Asia-Pacific Meeting, 1982 (Box 8)
  - Asia-Pacific staffing needs, 1982 (Box 8)
  - Backstop profile sheets, 1980 (Box 8)
  - Benefits trust (U.S.), 1981-1982 (Box 8)
  - Billing, 1981 (Box 8)
  - Bonus policy, 1982 (Box 8)
  - Bridge loan policy, 1980 (Box 8)
  - Budgets, 1982 (Box 8)
  - Career management, 1981 (Box 8)
  - Career planning, 1980 (Box 8)
  - Client conflict policy, 1979 (Box 8)
  - Compensation, 1979-1980 (Box 8)
  - Compensation, 1980-1982; 3 folders (Box 9)
  - Compensation--Executive compensation review, 1980-1981 (Box 9)
  - Compensation review, 1982; 3 folders (Box 9)
  - Compensation study, 1980 (Box 9)
  - Compensation study--Towers Perrin Forster & Crosby, 1979 (Box 9)
  - Computers, 1980 (Box 9)
  - Conflicts within offices, undated (Box 10)
  - Congratulations, 1981 (Box 10)
  - Corporate culture project, 1981-1982 (Box 10)
  - Corporate orientation, 1979-1981 (Box 10)
  - Creative, 1979-1982 (Box 10)
  - Creative film library, 1980 (Box 10)
  - Educational reimbursement, 1982 (Box 10)
  - EEO affirmative action, 1982 (Box 10)
  - EEO affirmative action plan, 1979 (Box 10)
  - Employee Personnel Data System, 1979 (Box 10)
  - Employee recognition, 1982 (Box 10)
  - Employee satisfaction survey (Roy W. Walters), undated (Box 10)
  - Employment applications forms, 1980 (Box 10)
  - Equal opportunity employment, 1980 (Box 10)
  - Evaluation forms, 1982 (Box 10)
  - Executive education programs, 1981 (Box 10)
  - Executive management, 1979 (Box 10)
  - Executive search firms, 1980-1982 (Box 10)
  - Exempt employees classification, 1980 (Box 10)
  - Field force, 1980 (Box 10)
  - Finance and Administrative Committee, 1980 (Box 10)
  - Financial, 1980-1982 (Box 10)
  - Fortune 500, 1980 (Box 10)
  - Freelance work policy, 1981 (Box 10)
  - Government contracts compliance, 1982 (Box 11)
  - Green file--International transfer candidates, 1981 (Box 11)
  - Hold file, 1981-1982 (Box 11)
  - Human Resources, 1979-1981; 2 folders (Box 11)
  - Human Resources--Business development opportunities, 1982 (Box 11)
  - Human Resources--Management, 1982-1983 (Box 11)
  - Human Resources--Management meetings, 1980 (Box 11)
  - Human Resources meetings, 1979-1980; 2 folders (Box 11)
  - Human Resources planning meeting, 1979 (Box 12)
  - Human Resources systems analysis, 1979 (Box 12)
  - Identification cards, 1980 (Box 12)
  - International personnel, 1979-1981 (Box 12)
  - International staffing principles, 1981 (Box 12)
  - International visitors lists, 1981-1982 (Box 12)
  - Internships, 1980 (Box 12)
  - James Kennedy biographical, 1980-1982 (Box 12)
  - James Kennedy speeches, 1980-1982; 2 folders (Box 12)
  - Job descriptions, 1979-1982 (Box 12)
  - JWT code of ethics, 1982 (Box 12)
  - JWT Fund, 1980-1982; 2 folders (Box 12)
  - JWT General Development Handbook, 1980 (Box 12)
  - JWT General Managers Handbook, 1981; 2 folders (Box 12)
  - JWT General Managers Handbook, 1981 (Box 13)
  - JWT Group Board Review, 1982 (Box 13)
  - JWT philosophy, 1979 (Box 13)
  - JWT retirement plan, 1981 (Box 13)
  - JWT Staffing System, 1980-1982 (Box 13)
  - JWT Staffing System--International, 1981 (Box 13)
  - JWT T-Plan, circa 1960 (Box 13)
  - JWT "The Meeting" social club, 1982 (Box 13)
  - JWT training program, 1979 (Box 13)
  - JWT--United Way, 1979 (Box 13)
  - Key job candidate summary sheet, 1981 (Box 13)
  - Legal Department, 1980 (Box 13)
  - Lever conference, 1981 (Box 13)
  - Management Incentive Program (MIP), 1980-1982; 3 folders (Box 13)
  - Management training (Troutbeck), 1981 (Box 13)
  - Managing human resources, 1980 (Box 13)
  - Marketing plan, 1981 (Box 13)
  - Media, 1980 (Box 13)
  - Nepotism policy, 1979 (Box 13)
  - New business, 1979-1980 (Box 13)
  - North American Operations meeting, 1979 (Box 14)
  - Office succession plans, 1982 (Box 14)
  - Officer nominations, 1980-1981 (Box 14)
  - Operations meeting, 1981 (Box 14)
  - Originals for new managers (handouts), 1981 (Box 14)
  - Overtime policy, 1980 (Box 14)
  - Performance appraisal, 1980 (Box 14)
  - Personal Development Handbook, 1981 (Box 14)
  - Personal Development Plan, 1980-1982; 4 folders (Box 14)
  - Personal T-Planning, 1980 (Box 15)
  - Personnel anniversaries, 1979-1981 (Box 15)
  - Personnel Department memos, 1979-1982 (Box 15)
  - Personnel meetings, agenda and correspondence, 1980 (Box 15)
  - Personnel Policies and Procedures Manual, 1980 (Box 15)
  - Personnel Policy Book, 1980-1981 (Box 15)
  - Personnel relocation, 1980 (Box 15)
  - Professional Development, 1980 (Box 15)
  - Professional Development--Learning Curve (firm), 1981 (Box 15)
  - Professional Development Plan (Mesico City Office), 1981 (Box 15)
  - Recruiting, 1979-1981 (Box 16)
  - Regional Directors--Staffing meetings, 1980-1982; 2 folders (Box 16)
  - Regional Directors--"Stars and Keepers" program, 1981 (Box 16)
  - Regional Directors--Succession planning, 1981-1982; 2 folders (Box 16)
  - Report--Human Resources Management, 1981 (Box 16)
  - Report--Marketing Revolution, 1981 (Box 16)
  - Secretarial, 1981 (Box 16)
  - Seminars, 1981 (Box 16)
  - Seminars, 1980-1982 (Box 17)
  - Seminars--Delavan, 1980-1982; 2 folders (Box 17)
  - Seminars--International Seminar Lima, 1980 (Box 17)
  - Seminars--Interview skills, 1982 (Box 17)
  - Seminars--James Webb Young, 1980 (Box 17)
  - Seminars--James Webb Young, Delavan, 1981; 2 folders (Box 17)
  - Seminars--James Webb Young, Lima, 1981 (Box 17)
  - Seminars--James Webb Young, Manila, 1981 (Box 17)
  - Seminars--James Webb Young, Segovia, 1981-1982 (Box 17)
  - Seminars--James Webb Young, Segovia, 1982 (Box 18)
  - Seminars--James Webb Young, Stressa, 1980 (Box 18)
  - Seminars--Noorowijk, 1980 (Box 18)
  - Seminars--Outplacement, 1981 (Box 18)
  - Seminars--Princeton, 1982 (Box 18)
  - Seminars--Sam Meek, Sao Paulo, 1982 (Box 18)
  - Seminars--Sam Meek, Stressa, 1981 (Box 18)
  - Solicitations, 1979-1981 (Box 18)
  - Stimulus and Response, 1979 (Box 18)
  - Stock options, 1982 (Box 18)
  - Strategic Organizational Effectiveness (Franck A. De Chambeau, AMA), 1982 (Box 18)
  - Succession Plan follow-up, 1982 (Box 18)
  - Succession Planning, 1981-1982 (Box 18)
  - Succession Planning II, 1982; 2 folders (Box 18)
  - Succession Planning Fact Book, 1981; 2 folders (Box 19)
  - Succession plans, 1981-1982 (Box 19)
  - Taxes, 1981 (Box 19)
  - Terminations correspondence, 1979-1981 (Box 19)
  - Training, 1982 (Box 19)
  - Transfer agreements (international), 1982 (Box 19)
  - Transfer agreements (U.S.), 1982 (Box 19)
  - Transfer issues, 1980 (Box 19)
  - Travel policy, 1980 (Box 19)
  - Turnover, 1980 (Box 19)
  - Union organizing--International examples, 1980 (Box 19)
  - U.S. Personnel meeting, 1980 (Box 19)
  - Vacation extension, 1979 (Box 19)
  - Visas--Correspondence, 1982 (Box 19)
  - William D. Laurie Scholarship, 1980 (Box 19)
  - Worldwide Agency, undated (Box 19)